

Software Engineer · Data Analyst
Stillwater OK

□ (+1) 303-642-6805 | ☑ caleb.cunningham@bigolbearconsulting.com | ⊙ threehoolagins | ☐ calebcunningham

Summary_

Current Fullstack Software Developer working at 3rd in industry Paycom, with previous experience in Data Platform roles such as GCP Pipeline maintenance or building new Data warehouse structures with Snowflake. DND nerd who loves what he does, and wants to help build the next future of products with code sustainability and ethical standards in front of mind from the first keystroke. Searching for my next big role where I can help develop a quality stable software product!

Work Experience _____

Paycom Oklahoma City, OK / Remote

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER III/IV

Oct 2022 - Current

- Refactored legacy employee app from PHP into ReactJS front-end with re-architected C# back-end enabled by PHP Restful API middlelayer
- Maintained C# Restful API with new MySQL supported endpoints
- · Maintained and Developed new features for PHP and AngularJS legacy system, clearing 30+ customer facing bugs and security vulbnerabilities
- Accurately tracked work through Jira tickets for both AGILE and Scrumban Practices
- Reviewed and approved Merge Requests using GitLab
- · Assisted in the growth of new developers by MR review and by volunteering to help them past sticking points

Big Ol' Bear Consulting LLC

Stillwater, OK

SOFTWARE CONSULTANT / FREELANCE

Oct 2023 - Current

Sift Science Remote

SOFTWARE ENGINEER & DATA ARCHITECT

Aug 2021 - Jul 2022

- Enabled better data governance using a Data Vault 2.0 structure for the Dispute management product, allowing better insights into fighting charge back fraud for customers.
- Created Airflow DAG to run SQL ETL on Snowflake to clean and transform data to Data Vault 2.0 Standards.
- Integrated Hashi Corp Vault secret authentication into Flyway process to remove plaintext secrets from our Data Warehouse management process.

Sift Science Remote

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING INTERN

Jun 2021 - Aug 2021

- Optimized General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) churned customer pipeline by restructuring Airflow DAG to reduce average weekly runtime by 30%
- Automated GDPR Right to Access (RTA) and Right to Object (RTO) processes using the Dropbox's Python API as part of greater airflow pipeline
 to save 5 hours of weekly engineer time and ensure Sift met GDPR SLAs for RTA requests

Education

Oklahoma State University

Stillwater, OK

B.S. IN COMPUTER ENGINEERING

Aug. 2017 - May. 2022

• Received Minor in computer science at time of completion.

Languages & Technologies

Passonate for Python, Confident in C#, Ready in React.js, Studied in Snowflake, Great with GCP, Hardened for Hashicorp Vault, Disciplined in Data Vault 2.0 Methodologies, Adept at Apache Airflow.